<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ruben-gz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.ruben-gz.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-24T08:16:06-07:00</updated><id>https://www.ruben-gz.com/feed.xml</id><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Orange Apartments, A Free Adobe Xd Website Template</title><link href="https://www.ruben-gz.com/Free-AdobeXD-Template-Apartment-Web-Finding-Service-Design" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orange Apartments, A Free Adobe Xd Website Template" /><published>2019-09-24T08:15:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-24T08:15:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.ruben-gz.com/Apartment-finding-web-service-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ruben-gz.com/Free-AdobeXD-Template-Apartment-Web-Finding-Service-Design">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;download-button&quot; href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/products/OVouL/edit&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\apartment-finding-web-app-service-design-free-adobe-xd-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;web design of apartment finding service realtor adobe xd free download&quot; title=&quot;Apartment Finding Website Application Design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\apartment-finding-service-web-design-desktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;web design of apartment finding service realtor adobe xd free download desktop version&quot; title=&quot;Apartment Finding Website Application Desktop Design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\apartment-finding-web-app-serice-design-free-adobe-xd-mobile-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;web design of apartment finding service realtor adobe xd free download mobile version&quot; title=&quot;Apartment Finding Website Application Design Mobile Responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-for-commercial-use&quot;&gt;Free For Commercial Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please link my website when using this template for any reason &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruben-gz.com&quot;&gt;ruben-gz.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ruben Gutierrez</name></author><summary type="html">Download</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Get More Customers Without Selling Your Kidney To AdWords</title><link href="https://www.ruben-gz.com/Website-Making-Guide-Keep-Kidney" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Get More Customers Without Selling Your Kidney To AdWords" /><published>2019-09-17T16:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T16:20:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.ruben-gz.com/Guide-Website-Building</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ruben-gz.com/Website-Making-Guide-Keep-Kidney">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\taking-kidney-google-ads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image of google ads taking kidney cartoon&quot; title=&quot;Google Ads Kidney Cartoon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a website can seem a little intimidating if you’ve never had to make one before, but I’m here to tell you it doesn’t have to be so hard.  Familiarizing yourself with the process of making a website can be a great skill to learn if you’re interested in making money online or creating &amp;amp; expanding an audience of people interested in your craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a small business and your looking to expand your reach, creating a website can be a very beneficial step in that direction. Not only will it help you gain attention online  and around the globe but it’ll help you be more recognizable in your local community, which is obviously more important to smaller businesses who rely on those around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I’ve condensed the process into 8 steps that make it a lot easier to understand if your new to online marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Properly putting a website together can be more financially beneficial to you than spending money on advertising with Google Ads or other traditional routes.  It brings customers to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timeline can look something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-collecting-information-about-the-purpose-and-goals-of-your-website&quot;&gt;Step 1 Collecting Information About The Purpose and Goals of Your Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\business-owner-developer-initial-meeting.png&quot; alt=&quot;website development initial meeting&quot; title=&quot;Initial Website Meeting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;establish-intent--goals&quot;&gt;Establish Intent &amp;amp; Goals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before any coding or designing ever gets done you need to have a conversation with the people creating your website about the purpose of your website and what it is your hope to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;brain-storming&quot;&gt;Brain Storming&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This initial part of the process is particularly important because it helps you establish how your website is going to look and feel.  An online shoe retailers website looks  and presents information different than a business whos focus is on plumbing services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-a-vision&quot;&gt;Creating A Vision&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailing your exact needs provides a mental image for the developers and designer who’ll create the website you want with the visuals and features you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-site-map--website-foundation&quot;&gt;Step 2 Site Map / Website Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\site-map-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;website site map example&quot; title=&quot;site map example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-a-site-map&quot;&gt;Creating A Site Map&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you’ve established intent and goals with the developer the next step is create a site map of your website with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-site-map&quot;&gt;What is A site map?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is a site map? A site map is a visual  representation of the  fundamental building blocks of your website. Site maps lay the foundation of your web site by visualizing the pages it’ll contain (e.g. about page, home page, blog page, etc…) along with establishing what will be inside of those main pages (e.g. the articles on the blog page, the sections on your about page, etc…)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-does-a-site-map-help&quot;&gt;How does a site map help?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site mapping is an important process because it helps you understand how the users are going to navigate through your website, it can aid in creating a more navigable and better experience for them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-wire-framing--website-mockup&quot;&gt;Step 3 Wire Framing / Website Mockup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\wire-frame-desktop-mobile-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;wire frame and website mock ups example for desktop and mobile website&quot; title=&quot;Wire frame mock ups for website on mobile and laptop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-a-wire-frame&quot;&gt;Creating A Wire Frame&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step involves taking all the information about your sitemap and allowing the developer to create wire frames of your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-wire-frame&quot;&gt;What is a wire frame?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is a wire frame? A wire frame is a basic mockup of your website without all the content, they let you get a good idea of what your websites interface is going to look like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-does-a-wire-frame-help-in-creating-a-website&quot;&gt;How does a wire frame help in creating a website?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wire framing is important because it helps build a visual hierarchy of your content. Wire frames let you get a good idea of how your users are going to process your information. They can help you and the developer create the best approach to presenting your content without including design visuals like font types, logos, images, and colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wire-frames-for-tablets-and-mobile&quot;&gt;Wire Frames for Tablets and Mobile&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wire frames also help you understand how your website is going to respond on mobile devices.  By framing your website you can be in control of how your website is going to form and adapt to fit different devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-creating-content-for-your-website&quot;&gt;Step 4 Creating Content For Your Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\Web-content-video-written-gallery-example-icons.png&quot; alt=&quot;website content examples image&quot; title=&quot;Diffrent types of content for your website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-does-web-content-help-my-website&quot;&gt;How does web content help my website?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making content for your website in my opinion the most important part of the process.  Here you can get a good sense of how well your website is going to perform especially in the search engines like Google, Bing, &amp;amp; Yahoo.  If you have good informative content that people like and frequent then you can expect to see a rise in visits. The longer someone stays on your website, the more likely they are to purchase your products or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-website-content&quot;&gt;What is website content?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content for you websites ranges all the way from deciding on images and page headers and introduction to creating informative visual and written articles.  Content can also be more leisure things like funny images and videos, it all really depends on what field your in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-content-timeline&quot;&gt;Creating Content Timeline&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing and creating the content for a website is a step that can occur anywhere along the process but is usually implemented after wire framing and right before the final designs and development are done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;who-should-write-the-content-on-my-website&quot;&gt;Who should write the content on my website?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re usually required to provide the information/content that is going to be displayed on the website.You can also hire outside sources to help you and in rare occasion ask the developer.  If nothing else you can create the content for your website, after all who knows your business and line of work better than you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;posting-new-content&quot;&gt;Posting New Content&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting new content is a great way to stay connected with your customers and to gain some new one.  Blog post can make you look well informed and can be very resourceful to your returning users, it also serves as way of letting people know your still active on your site and are ready for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-final-design&quot;&gt;Step 5 Final Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\final-website-design-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Final website design for web development&quot; title=&quot;Website Final Designs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;discussing-the-design&quot;&gt;Discussing the Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have both the content and rough layout of your website you can talk to the designer about how to best present your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;finalizing-appearance&quot;&gt;Finalizing Appearance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design portion of creating a website includes deciding on features like colors, element sizing, animation types, fonts, and graphic designs.  Everything discussed in the first step  (Step #1 Collecting Information About The Purpose and Goals of Your Website)  should be kept at the front of yours and the designers mind when creating the final design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-design-before-production&quot;&gt;Final Design Before Production&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final rendition of your website should include everything decided up until this point. It’s the clearest picture of your website until it’s actually developed in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;client-approval&quot;&gt;Client Approval&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is important to the designer, adjustments should be made accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-6-website-development--coding&quot;&gt;Step 6 Website Development / Coding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\website-coding-programming.png&quot; alt=&quot;Images of People Programming a Website&quot; title=&quot;Web Development Process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;coding-the-website&quot;&gt;Coding the Website&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you’ve given the approval to the final design comes the step most people are familiar with, coding the website.  Here the web developers takes all the designs, features and ideas and programs the final version of your website.  They should keep in mind everything you’ve requested and implement your ideas using the appropriate tools and code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;familiarizing-yourself-with-the-tools&quot;&gt;Familiarizing Yourself with The Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your needs the developer should brief you on what tools fit best for you, understanding the tools can be the difference between spending a few dozen dollars or spending nothing at all in order to edit your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-7-deployment-checklist&quot;&gt;Step 7 Deployment Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\website-deployment-checklist.png&quot; alt=&quot;A website checklist for deployment&quot; title=&quot;Website Deployment Checklist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;reviewing-details&quot;&gt;Reviewing Details&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before your website goes live on the internet, you and the developer should run through a checklist to make sure everything’s in order and assure everything goes smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pre-deployment-website-checklist&quot;&gt;Pre Deployment Website Checklist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your checklist should look something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure every link goes to the correct URL and isn’t broken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to see if forms are being properly submitted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure all the designs match&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to see if all the content is properly present&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spell Check entire website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to see if the website is responsive on all devices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to see if your using the most up to date software’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure your site has a sitemap.xml file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure your website has title and descriptions for SEO purposes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure your website is compatible for all browser&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up analytics to track website visitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deploying-website&quot;&gt;Deploying Website&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you’ve gone over this list and everything is good your developer can deploy your website to a server.  Most people upload their website to a remote server for a fee, but you can also use other options like Github Pages and deploy a live static website for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-8-maintenance&quot;&gt;Step 8 Maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\img\blog-images\19-september\website-maintenance-gear-icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;website maintenance gear icons&quot; title=&quot;Website Maintenenace Gear Icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ongoing-maintenance--updating&quot;&gt;Ongoing Maintenance &amp;amp; Updating&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a website finally goes up it’s important to remember that the work hasn’t ended yet.  Although a website usually functions well when properly put together things happen overtime (e.g. code becomes outdated, content management systems update, layouts become yesterday’s look, information edits etc…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hiring-the-right-people&quot;&gt;Hiring the Right People&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to keep an eye on your website and to hire the right people to work on it to keep it modern and secure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ruben Gutierrez</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>